# **Jhonatan** Oliveira



Jhonatan Oliveira 👤 08/02/1991

Brazil 🏲

jhonatanoliveira@gmail.com +1-306-5804930 

◆ https://jhonatanoliveira.github.io

# PROFILE

A third-year Ph.D. student in Computer Science researching probabilistic graphical models and generative deep learning models. Several academic publications including a recent paper at the top tier conference AAAI 2019. Research projects involving theoretical development and implementation of machine learning models. including Sum-Product networks, generative adversarial networks (GANs), Bayesian networks, and Markov networks. Bachelor in Electrical Engineering with experience in robotics, parallel and numerical programming, and general artificial intelligence algorithms. Extensive programming experience with Python, C++, and Java, and some experience with Matlab and OCaml. Professional web development experience in JavaScript (Node.js, Angular, Meteor.js), PHP (CakePHP, Zend), Python (Django, Flask), and Java (Struts2), including mobile development with Cordova and NativeScript / React Native.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

08/2018 - present **Senior Software Engineer** Gign, Regina, Canada

Part-time position managing a small developer team in a startup company developing a mobile app focusing on the music/video streaming market. Duties involve designing technical documentation, automated tests, project deployment, reviewing and supervising developers.

**Software Engineer Intern** 08/2011 - 09/2012 SYDLE, Vicosa, Brazil

Member of a medium-sized software development team working in a system for power contract management. Development performed in Java using an internal framework (inspired on Struts2). Familiar with tools such as Eclipse IDE, database (Oracle), revision control system (CVS), and MVC/ORM design patterns. I was being trained for a System Analyst position.

Web Developer 06/2010 - 12/2010Universidade Federal de Viçosa, Viçosa, Brazil

Web developer for the university internal systems using frameworks in PHP language, database (MySQL), JavaScript (jQuery), and Ajax operations. Familiar with concepts such as design patterns

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Model. View and Controller (MVC) and Object-Relational Mapping (ORM).

**Linux Network** 01/2010 - 06/2010 **Administrator** 

Universidade Federal de Viçosa, Viçosa, Brazil Manager of Linux computer network. Familiar with Linux distributions such as Debian, Ubuntu, and Fedora. Maintained protocols including LTSP and DHCP.

01/2007 - 06/2007 Computer Instructor Data Prom Informática, Coronel Fabriciano, Brazil Instructor at a computer learning centre teaching basic concepts such as operational systems (Linux and Windows) and office suits (Word, Excel, PowerPoint).

# EDUCATION

**PhD in Computer Science** 09/2016 - present University of Regina, Regina, Canada

**MSc in Computer Science** 01/2015 - 08/2016University of Regina, Regina, Canada

**Bachelor in Electrical** 01/2009 - 12/2014 **Engineering** 

Universidade Federal de Viçosa, Viçosa, Brazil



**Artificial Intelligence** 

**Deep Learning** 

**Machine Learning** 

**Neural Networks** 

**Probabilistic Models** 

**Bayesian networks** 

**Python** 

C++

Java

**Software Engineering** 

**Web Development** 

**Mobile Applications** 

**JavaScript** 

**HTML** 

**CSS** 

React.is

**Angular** 

**MonaoDB** 

**NativeScript** 

**PHP** 

**Amazon Web Services (AWS)** 

Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

**Robotics** 

Matlab

**OCaml** 

# LANGUAGES





Portuguese

English

# AWARDS

**Science Without Borders** 01/2013 Coordenação de Aperfeicoamento de Pessoal de

Nível Superior (CAPES)

Science Without Borders scholarship from the Brazilian government, an exchange student scholarship to study during one year at the University of Regina, Canada. Value: \$65,023.41 BRL (~ 22,500 CAD)

**Graduate Studies** 

01/2015

Scholarship Scholarly Award

University of Regina Value: \$6,000 CAD

**Graduate Studies** 05/2015 Scholarship Scholarly

Award

University of Regina

**Graduate Studies** 

Value: \$6,000 CAD

09/2015 Scholarship Scholarly

Award

University of Regina Value: \$3,000 CAD

# AWARDS

**Graduate Studies Scholarship Scholarly** 

Award

University of Regina Value: \$6,000 CAD

**Graduate Studies Research** 

09/2016

01/2016

**Fellowship** 

University of Regina

Value: \$22,623.38 CAD per year for up to 4 years



#### **Convolutional Neural Networks**

12/2017

10/2017

Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishme nts/verify/MX965WE5BCPA

Improving Deep Neural **Networks: Hyperparameter** tuning, Regularization and

**Optimization** 

Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishme nts/verify/4DPFU2SJUGFH

#### Structuring Machine **Learning Projects**

10/2017

Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishme nts/verify/CY7FH4WP37Z7

#### **Neural Networks and Deep** Learning

09/2017

Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishme nts/verify/2Q8977CRUM3D

# **Probabilistic Graphical**

05/2017

Models 1: Representation

Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishme nts/verify/TM7KHT24EBQV

#### Machine Learning

06/2014

Coursera

https://jhonatanoliveira.github.io/files/Coursera\_C ertificate\_v1-972224147177.pdf

#### **Data Mining with Weka**

04/2014

The University of Waikato

https://jhonatanoliveira.github.io/files/mooccertificate-dmww-2014%20235.pdf









Purple belt in jiu-jitsu

Theatre actor / director

(Audio)books / Music enthusiast